最后让我来个点睛之笔...
And now for the finishing touch...
煎饼先生笑脸的樱桃鼻子
Mr. Pancake smileyface gets a cherry nose.
太可爱了  你是给查莉做的吧
That's so cute. Is that for Charlie?
呃  是啊  为查莉做的
Uh, yeah, for Charlie.
谢谢
Thank you.
嘿  亲爱的  我告诉你个好消息
Hey, honey, I've got some great news.
城里那家豪华酒店
There was a bedbug infestation.
闹虫灾了...
At this really nice hotel downtown...
鲍伯  这有啥让你兴奋的
Bob, it is amazing what gets you excited.
总之
Anyway,
酒店经理对于我的工作很满意
the manager of the hotel was so pleased with the job I did.
于是他就允许咱们周六晚
He's letting us stay
去他那里最浪漫的套房里住一晚
in their most romantic suite this Saturday night.
太好了
That's great!
你确定你的工作做彻底了吗
You did get rid of all the bedbugs, right?
亲爱的  这又不是什么严谨的科学
It's not an exact science, honey.
重点是咱可以免费入住
The point is it's free!
好吧  现在只有一个难题了...谁来照顾查莉
Well, there's just one catch... who's gonna watch Charlie?
我们来  我们很有责任心的
We'll do it. We're very responsible.
不用绝望...我也会来帮忙的
Don't worry... I'll be here too.
-好为你俩感动啊  -是啊
-You guys are great. -All right!
我们终于有信得过的孩子了
It sure is nice to have kids we can trust.
包括PJ
And P.J.
咱开个派对吧  你说啥
Let's throw a party! Wait what?
好了  我先说  我说咱们等爸妈走后
No, me first. I said let's throw a party.
开个派对吧
When mom and dad are out of the house.
你怎么堕落了
When do you ever do bad things?
我一直可以堕落的
I can be bad.
我还可以堕落得很深呢
I can be very bad.
-吹牛  -你不信
-Cannot. -Oh yeah?
-不信  -看好了
-Uh-huh. -Watch this.
我要直接对嘴喝牛奶
I'm gonna drink milk right out of the carton.
因为我堕落了
Because I'm bad.
你打算咽下去吗
Are you gonna swallow?
嗯嗯
Huh-uh.
-你打算吐出来吗  -嗯嗯
-You wanna spit it out? -Mm-hmm.
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录 www.Deefun.com
生活搞得一团糟
<i>Today's all burnt toast </i>
就要迟到  爸爸在叫
<i>Running late, and dad jokes</i>
我左脚的鞋子有没有人看到
<i>Has anybody seen my left shoe</i>
■
翻译： Johnny-Z
我闭上眼  咬口早餐
<i>I close my eyes, take a bite</i>
■
校订： line
跳上车子  放声大笑
<i>Grab a ride, laugh out loud</i>
哎呀  老爸  鞋子就在房顶上
<i>There it is up on the roof</i>
我也曾这样生活  我已经顺利走过
<i>I've been there, I've survived</i>
■
后期： Johnny-Z
所以听取我的建议
<i>So just take my advice</i>
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby</i>
世界有很多疯狂无奈
<i>Things are crazy</i>
可是我知道你会有美好将来
<i>But I know your future's bright</i>
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby</i>
不要怀疑
<i>There's no maybe</i>
一切终会如你所愿
<i>Everything turns out all right</i>
生活有悲有喜
<i>Your life is up and down</i>
但是请相信我  坚持就有好结果
<i>But trust me it comes back around</i>
你会喜欢将来的你
<i>You're gonna love</i> <i>who you turn out to be</i>
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby.</i>
查莉成长日记  第二季第五集
Good Luck Charlie  S02E05  Duncan vs Duncan
老妈  你想去开门吗
Mom, you wanna get that?
太好了  还想让我怎么样
Great! What's next?
我自己造张床吗
Making my own bed?
-嘿  乔  -你胳膊怎么打上石膏了
-Hey, Jo. -Why is your arm in a cast?
噢  我手指摔断了
Oh, I broke my finger.
是这样的  我在打棒球...
See, I was playing baseb...
好了  还是听我说吧
Okay, now back to me.
我老妈非要让我去
My mom says I have to go.
一种叫做沙龙舞的傻缺玩意
To this stupid thing called cotillion.
说是那傻缺课程可以提高你的个人修养
It's a stupid class where they reach you manners
社交能力
and social graces.
以及其他什么傻缺能力  由于这个傻缺的舞蹈
And other stupid stuff. And there's a stupid dance.
我不得不找个傻缺的舞伴
And I have to bring a stupid date.
于是我就想到了你
So I thought of you.
我不去  拜拜了
Pass. Bye-bye now.
噢  别这样  盖比  我觉着这个沙龙舞
Oh come on, Gabe. I think it'd be.
对于你来说再合适不过了
A great idea for you to go to cotillion.
噢  现在你出现了
Oh, now you show up.
别这样嘛  我给你弄套西服
Come on, I'll get you a little suit,
然后我们再给乔弄个可爱的胸花
we'll get Jo a lovely corsage.
相信我  你会喜欢上的
Trust me, you'll love it.
以前你提到所以那些“我会喜欢”的东西
Ever notice the things you say I'm gonna love
我有喜欢过吗
I never love?
没有
Yeah.
盖比会去的
Gabe's looking forward to it.
今晚上再见  傻缺
See you tonight, stupid.
看来她还真需要提高社交能力
Not that she needs any social graces.
难道我在这里一点发言权都没有吗
So I don't have a say in this?
你就强行拉着我去了
You're just gonna force me to go?
噢  宝贝  那也是作为父母的乐趣之一
Oh, sweetie, that's part of the fun of being a parent.
另外  我希望至少我有一位孩子会懂得礼仪
Besides, I want at least one of my kids to have manners.
老妈  热狗面包没了
Mom, we're out of buns.
不用商量了  你去定了
Oh yeah, you're going.
好了  试试这个  张嘴
Okay, try this one. Open up.
好了
Okay.
脆脆的
Crunchy,
还很滑溜
And smooth.
那是玉米片加上一勺花生酱
It's a corn chip with a scoop of peanut butter.
我叫它玉米酱
I call it a corn butt.
味道不错
It's good.
但是名字得再取一个
Needs a new name.
嘿
Hey.
你哥俩个啥呢
What are you guys doing?
尝尝为派对准备的零食
Testing snacks for the party.
来尝尝...花生片
Care for a... Butt chip?
你看我来准备零食怎么样
How about I handle the snacks?
噢  泰迪
Oh, um, Teddy?
-很期待这个派对吧  -是啊
-Looking forward to the party? -Mm-hmm.
我能和你跳第一支舞吗
May I have the first dance?
你嘴里都是花生片味儿
You have butt chip breath.
我去刷牙了
I'll go brush.
我当时正在被人欺负  而你应该为我撑腰
I was being insulted and you should have defended me!
我撑不了...因为你把我陷于尴尬之地
I couldn't... too busy being embarrassed by you.
怎么了
What's going on?
去问那个被杂货店轰出来的女人
Ask the woman who just got kicked out of the grocery store.
当时我在购物付款快速通道结账
I was standing in the 15-items-or-less line.
（注：低于15件商品可以在此通道快速结账）
-在想着心事...  -却拿着十七件商品
-Just minding my own business... -With 17 items.
...有个疯婆子在我们后面排队
... When this crazy woman in line behind us.
然后就开始冲我喊  不让我在这个通道结账
Starts screaming at me to get out of line.
此时你老妈处理得很好
Your mother handled it well though.
抓起标价枪  就冲着那女人的脸一通狂扫
Grabbed the pricing gun, scanned the woman's face.
在我和那个疯婆子的整个战斗中
And through this entire ugly confrontation.
你爸爸就在那傻站着  像个白痴一样吃着甜甜圈
Your father stood there, like an oaf, eating a donut.
我在努力尝试把商品减到十五件
I was trying to get us down to 15 items.
PJ  请转告你爸爸
P.J., tell your father.
直到他为他懦弱的表现而道歉
That I will not be speaking to him.
我是不会再和他说话的
Until he apologizes for not backing me up.
算你狠  泰迪  麻烦转告你妈妈
Okay. Teddy, tell your mother
我不会道歉的
I will not apologize.
还有直到她不为她陷我于尴尬之地而道歉
And that <i>I</i> will not be speaking to <i>her</i>
我也不会和她说话的
Until <i>she</i> apologizes for embarrassing <i>me.</i>
哇  还好我还没娶老婆呢
Whoa, glad I didn't get that one.
晚上好大家  欢迎来参加沙龙舞培训班
Good evening and welcome to cotillion.
我是克伦普先生
I am Mr. Krump.
我是克伦普夫人
And I am Mrs. Krump.
我一定要报复老妈
And I am planning revenge on my mother.
今天晚上过得愉快吗  克伦普先生
How are you this evening, Mr. Krump?
非常好  谢谢  你呢  克伦普夫人
Very well, thank you. And you, Mrs. Krump?
我也非常好  谢谢  克伦普先生
Oh, very well, Mr. Krump. Thank you.
我对这俩人的憎恨之情油然而生
I have never hated two people so fast before.
现在我们要学的是
Now we'll be learning the art.
如何称赞某人的晚宴同伴
Of complimenting one's dinner partner.
克伦普夫人  您看起来美极了
You look very lovely this evening, Mrs. Krump.
你也看起来很英俊啊  克伦普先生
And you look most handsome, Mr. Krump.
现在  同学们  该你们了  称赞下你的同伴
Now, children, your turn. Compliment your partners.
晚上好  基纳小姐
Good evening, miss keener.
你的双眼犹如克伦普夫人大腿上的静脉一样蓝
Your eyes are as blue as the vein on Mrs. Krump's leg.
谢谢夸奖  邓肯先生
Why, thank you, Mr. Duncan.
我必须要说下你的石膏
And may I say your cast is as green.
犹如克伦普先生抠出来的鼻屎一样绿
As the booger peeking out of Mr. Krump's nose?
现在  绅士们  护送你们的女士
Now, gentlemen, escort your ladies.
到桌旁就座
To a table and take your seats.
当用餐时  正确使用餐具
Now when dining, it is most important.
是最重要的
To use the proper utensils.
拿起你们最小的勺子
So pick up your smallest spoon.
来品尝下蜜瓜球吧
And enjoy some melon balls.
基纳小姐  尝尝这个
Here, miss keener, enjoy this.
技术不错啊  邓肯先生
Exeellent technique, Mr. Duncan.
但如果你用下汤匙
But if you use your soup spoon.
你就能一下品尝两个了
You can have twice the enjoyment.
噢
Oh!
那我也试试
I believe I'll give that a try.
噢  噢  噢  噢
Oh ho ho! Oh ho ho.
好了  好了
All right, all right.
谁干的
Who did that?
噢  您干啥呢
Oh, what are you doing?
那个  自从我不再和你老妈说话后
Well, since I'm no longer talking to your mother,
我想我今晚只能睡这里了
I figured I'd sleep down here tonight.
-噢  太惨了  -我没事的
-Oh, I'm sorry. -I'll be all right.
我是说沙发太惨了
I'm talking to the couch.
下次你再需要给你车上保险时
Next time you need your car insurance paid,
和沙发说去
Talk to the couch.
呃  老爸  这么看来
Uh, so, dad,
明晚你和老妈依旧按计划来
Are you and mom still planning on going.
去那酒店享受一晚吗
To that hotel tomorrow night?
除非她先道歉
Not unless she apologizes.
她绝对不会道任何歉的
<i>She</i> will be doing nothing of the sort.
-我还以为你不和我说话呢  -我没有
-I thought you weren't talking to me. -I wasn't.
-你就是说了  -你也和我说了
-You just did. -So did you.
太完美了  你俩之间又有对话了
Well, this is nice. You've got a dialogue going.
-白痴  -疯婆子
-Oaf. -Lunatic.
噢  PJ  坏事了
Oh, P.J., is is bad.
他们要是不去酒店
If they don't go to the hotel tomorrow night
咱们还怎么开派对啊
then we can't have our party.
-除非...  -除非什么
-Unless... -Unless what?
-除非他们...  -除非他们什么
-Unless they... -Unless they what?
我只能想到这里了  后面的想不出来了
I got the ball rolling here. I can't think of everything.
迈步  转身  下腰
Step and turn and dip.
结束
And done.
现在我们请上来一组同学
Now let's have a couple of students on the floor.
来示范下位置
To demonstrate the position.
那就请上
How about.
蜜瓜发射者吧
The melon launchers?
现在请这位绅士...也就是
Now the gentleman... or in this case.
你...
You...
握住他的左手
Holds his left hand thusly.
然后你的右手
And his right hand.
搂住这位女士的腰部
Around the lady's waist.
很好  现在你俩靠近点
All right, now move in a little closer.
她又不咬人
She's not going to bite.
没错  但她会揍我和踢我
Yes, but she will punch and kick.
这倒是实话  我的确可以做到
It's true. I do that.
再靠近点
Move a little closer.
快点  很好
Closer! There you go.
好了  绅士们  快和你们的同伴摆好姿势
All right, gentlemen, please address your partners.
太诡异了
This is weird.
-没啥诡异的  -你很享受这个
-It's not so weird. -You like it?
是啊  有点儿
Yeah, kinda.
咿呦  你居然很享受
Ew! You like it.
-那又怎样  -太恶心了
-So? -So it's gross.
我才不要当你的男朋友
I don't want to be your boyfriend.
-我还不想当你的女朋友呢  -很好
-I don't want to be your girlfriend. -Good!
-很好  -我走了
-Good! -I'm outta here.
随便
Fine!
别着急  他会回来的
Don't worry. He'll be back.
他们总会乖乖地回来的
They always come back.
然后就悔恨终身
And regret it for the rest of their lives.
听着  老爸
Look, dad,
-我知道你是无辜的  -我也知道
-I know you're right. -And I know you're right.
但到一天结束之时  你是喜欢无辜呢
But at the end of the day would you rather be right...
还是喜欢开心呢
Or would you rather be happy?
-那个...  -开心
-Well... -Happy.
答案是开心
The answer's happy.
而您所要做的就是向老妈去道歉
All you have to do is just apologize to mom.
求您放下架子
And if you can't do it for yourself,
就当是为了孩子们
Do it for the kids.
好吧  给你们个面子
All right, maybe you're right.
这就对了  老爸
Attaboy, dad.
耶  耶  耶
Yeah yeah yeah.
话说  您应该已经习惯去和老妈道歉了
And besides, you should be used to apologizing to mom by now.
反正您好像已经做过一百次一样
You've done it like 100 times.
是吗  我有吗
I have, haven't I?
我向你妈道了一百次歉  而我没得到过任何道歉
That makes the score mom 100, dad nothing.
老爸  我说像是道过一百次歉一样
Dad, I said like 100 to nothing.
也许都有两百次了  只是我们不知道而已
Maybe it's 200 to nothing, we don't know.
别听他瞎扯  快去吧  快  快  快
Don't listen to him, just go go go!
就当为了孩子们
For the kids.
我不去道歉了
I'm not apologizing.
我就是无辜的
I'm right.
我告诉你们  今天过后
And you know what? After today.
我将会把比分扳为一百
The score is going to be mom 100,
比一
Dad 1.
-到底怎么回事  -你给搞砸了
-What just happened here? -You blew it.
你又开始扯上数字了
You started using numbers.
可恶的数学
Stupid math.
如今咱们只能取消派对了
Now we're gonna have to cancel the party.
不成  现在太晚了
No, we can't do that. It's too late.
我还是去说服老妈去道歉吧
I'll just have to talk to mom and get her to apologize.
虽然前方荆棘丛生  但我会勇往直前的
It won't be easy, but I can do it.
-毕竟是亲骨肉  -没错
-Fortunately we have a special bond. -Mmm.
-老妈...  -我是不会去道歉的
-Mom... -I'm not apologizing.
晚安
Good night.
好了  PJ  再试一遍
Okay, P.J., try one more time.
-好了  查莉  你怎么了  -我伤心了
-Okay, Charlie, what's the matter? -I'm sad.
查莉  为什么伤心呢
Why are you sad, Charlie?
妈咪和爹地吵架了
Mommy and daddy fight.
好啊  真棒  查莉
Yes, good job, Charlie.
试下不要面带笑容的说  因为你很伤心
Just try not to say it with a smile. You're sad.
一定要入戏
Let us feel your pain.
-她才两岁  -就不能演的敬业点吗
-She's two. -So she can't give us a good performance?
好吧  查莉
All right, Charlie,
施展你的魔力  让我们的派对回来吧
work your magic so we can have our party.
-好了  -好了
-All right. -Okay.
-准备好  -好的
-Come on. -Okay.
老妈  老爸  快进来
Mom, dad, get in here.
-怎么了  -没事吧
-What's going on? -Everything okay?
查莉好像不高兴了
Charlie seems very upset.
查莉  告诉妈咪和爹地怎么了
Charlie, tell mommy and daddy what's the matter.
派对
Party.
Party!
为什么她一直在说派对
Why does she keep saying party?
不要在乎她说的什么
Just stop focusing on what she just said.
在乎下她刚才说的
Focus on what she said before,
她刚才说的“我很伤心
Which was "I sad.
妈咪和爹地吵架了”
Mommy and daddy fight."
没错  她又说“我好希望他们能和好
Yeah, and then she said, "I just wish they'd make up.
可以去那套超浪漫的套房度假”
And go to the romantic suite at the hotel."
-那都是你说的  -派对
-You said all that? -Party!
嗨  欢迎欢迎
Hi, welcome to the party.
计划有变  你们要去房子那边
Little change of plans. You want to go around the house.
的窗户那里  然后从窗户爬进地下室
To that window over there and climb in through the basement.
我爸妈在家呢
My mom and dad are home.
这是一场无声的派对
So this is going to be a quiet party.
我们不能弄出任何声音
We're not gonna make any noise.
现在去好好玩吧
Now go have fun.
嗨  计划有变
Hi, little change of plans.
艾米
Amy?
怎么了  鲍伯
Yes, Bob?
沙发哪去了
Where's the couch?
就是你以前睡过的那老古董吗
Oh, that old thing you've been sleeping on?
我送出去清理了
I sent it out to be cleaned.
不觉着清理沙发
You know, usually when they clean a couch,
只需要在房间里清理就够了吗
They clean it when it's still in the home.
这个嘛  清理人员想弄走  就弄走了
Well, couch cleaners-to-go takes it to go.
我猜可能会有特殊清理程序的
I guess they have some sort of special process.
那好吧
Very well,
看来我只能睡在地下室的沙发了
I guess I'll be sleeping on the couch in the basement then.
是吗  恐怕也不成了
Yeah, I don't think so.
他们有买一送一活动
They were having a two-for-one special.
别自作聪明了  别忘了车库里有个气垫床
You think you're so smart. There's an air mattress in the garage.
扔了
Popped it!
嘿  嘿  派对之王们
Hey! Hey, party animals.
这是纸笔  记住要用这东西交流
Here's a pen and paper, chat amongst yourselves.
好了
Okay.
你
What?!
我怎么说的  调成震动
What did I say?! Vibrate only!
埃米特  埃米特  把你兜里的零钱掏出来
Emmett! Emmett, take the change out of your pockets.
噢  好的
Oh, right.
噢
Oh!
老爸来了
Dad's coming!
大家都撤回我的房间  快  快
Everybody into my room. Go go go.
快  快  快
Go go go!
啊
Ahhh!
楼下没事吧
Everything okay down here?
没事  我们挺好的
Yeah, we're fine.
我是说  没事  我们挺好的
I mean, yeah, we're fine.
-我刚才好像听见有什么动静  -没有
-I thought I heard noises. -No no.
根本没什么动静啊  老爸
No. No noises down here, dad.
只是兄妹间叙叙旧
Just down to the brother and sister getting along.
嗷
Ow.
嘿  亲...  怎么回事
Hey, hon... what?
你怎么没去跳沙龙舞
Why aren't you dressed for cotillion?
我不去了  我和乔吵架了
I'm not going. Jo and I had a fight.
-为什么事啊  -他们让我们跳舞要离近点
-What happened? -They made us dance really close.
而乔居然很享受这个  好恶心啊
And she liked it! It was gross.
只有一天就让你崩溃了
Well, one day you'll feel different.
你可想而知那二十年周而复始
Then 20 years will go by.
的恶心你  是什么滋味了
And it will be gross all over again.
盖比  乔来了
Gabe, Jo's here.
-盖比  -抱歉  你说什么
-Gabe! -I'm sorry, what?
我说给快给我那傻缺的花儿  你个傻缺
I said give me my stupid flower, stupid.
哇
Wow.
现在不恶心了  是不
Not so gross now, huh?
等她回来
Just wait.
还有什么能补偿给您的吗  基纳小姐
Is there anything I can get you, miss keener?
除了退款...那个我不能补偿
I mean besides a refund... which I can't get you.
我只是想上完这课程
I'm just here to pass the class.
晚上好  基纳小姐
Good evening, miss keener.
傻缺  你来干嘛
What are you doing here, stupid?
能请你跳支舞吗
May I have this dance?
谢了
Thanks.
刚才真是...
That was...
算了
Okay.
晚餐开始了  大家
Dinner, everyone, dinner.
-我给你个惊喜  -是吗  什么惊喜
-I have a surprise for you. -Really? What is it?
我往克伦普夫人的沙拉里放了几只蚯蚓
I put some earthworms into Mrs. Krump's salad.
我想她现在应该...
And she should be finding them right about...
发现了
Now.
噢  基纳小姐  你真是我的开心果
Oh, miss keener, you are a delight.
鲍伯  死哪去了
Bob! Where is he?
什么  又抽什么疯呢
What? For heaven's sakes.
你干嘛呢
What are you doing?
好了  对不起  成了吧
Fine. I'm sorry, okay?
你说什么
What's that?
我没听见
I didn't hear you.
别让我再说第二遍了
Don't make me say it again.
不是不是  我是说我真没听见你说什么
No no no, I mean I really didn't hear you.
我耳朵好像冻僵了
I think my ears froze.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我错了
I was wrong.
我在杂货店的表现很差劲
And I behaved badly in the grocery store.
我也不应该让你难堪
And I shouldn't have embarrassed you.
天啊  这说起来太困难了
Man, this is hard.
我都不知道你是怎么完成162次的
I don't know how you've done it 162 times.
因为我爱你
It's because I love you.
嗯  我也爱你
Mmm, I love you.
抱抱
Come here.
你知道有个地下派对在进行吧
You know there's a secret party going on downstairs?
是啊  我当然知道了
Yeah, of course I do.
看来咱俩要教训教训他们了
You know we're gonna have to punish them?
我来打头阵
I'm way ahead of you.
老妈  老爸  我们知错了
Mom, dad, we get it.
好了  对不起啊  我们不会再犯了
Okay, we're sorry. We'll never do it again.
-这样惩罚我们还不够吗  -洒舞
-Haven't we been punished enough? -Sprinkler?
噢对  洒舞  来一段
Oh, sprinkler, yes, definitely.
-天啊  天啊...  -不要啊
-Whoosh, whoosh... -No!
嗨  查莉  不要抱有侥幸心理干坏事
Hi, Charlie. So finally tried doing something bad.
结果不会如愿以偿的
It didn't turn out so good.
我被惩罚惨了
I got punished.
-鬼步舞  -鬼步舞
-Running man. -Running man?
没错  惩罚还在继续
Yep, and I'm still being punished.
所以要时刻保持乖乖女的形象  不然就...
So always try and be a good girl, because if not...
鹅颈舞
Gooseneck!
好了  祝你好运吧  查莉
Yeah, good luck, Charlie.
如此高雅  如此镇定
So elegant, so poised.
真是太有教养了
Such sophistication.
克伦普夫人  这是我们最得意的门生
Our finest pupil ever, Mrs. Krump.
坏了
Uh-oh.
克伦普夫人  她就是邓肯家最后的一个孩子了吧
She's the last of the Duncan kids, right, Mrs. Krump?
希望如此  克伦普先生
One can only hope, Mr. Krump.